export const quiz = {
  totalQuestions: 5,
  questions: [
    {
      id: 1,
      question: 'The conversation between Nagasena and Menander-I related to Buddhism is recorded in which book?',
      answers: ['Milindapanho',
        'Panhomenanda',
        'Nagapanho',
        'Menandapanho]'],
      correctAnswer: 'Milindapanho',
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      question: 'Who among the following was the first Satavahana King to introduce the Ruler’s head on the coins ?',
      answers: ['Satkarni I',
      'Gautamiputra Satkarni',
      'Vasishthiputra Pulumavi',
      'Yajna Satakarni]'],
      correctAnswer: 'Satkarni I',
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      question: 'In which Buddhist Council, Buddhism was divided into Mahayana and Hinayana sects?',
      answers: ['First Buddhist Council',
      'Second Buddhist Council',
      'Third Buddhist Council',
      'Fourth Buddhist Council'],
      correctAnswer: 'Fourth Buddhist Council',
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      question: 'Which among the following is the correct location of an ancient site Deh Morasi Ghundai?',
      answers: ['Northern Pakistan',
      'Eastern Persia',
      'Modern Turkey',
      'Afghanistan'],
      correctAnswer: 'Afghanistan',
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      question: 'Who defeated the Saka king Rudrasimha III and annexed his kingdom?',
      answers: ['Ramagupta',
      'Chandragupta II',
      'Kumargupta I',
      'Samudragupta'],
      correctAnswer: 'Chandragupta II',
    },
    {
      id: 6,
      question: 'Which of the following was main capital of Kushana king Kanishka-I?',
      answers: ['Purushapura',
      'Pataliputra',
      'Taxila',
      'Mathura'],
      correctAnswer: 'Purushapura',
    },
    {
      id: 7,
      question: 'Which of the following regions was called “Gedrosia” during times of Alexander, the great?',
      answers: ['Gujarat',
      'Rajasthan',
      'Punjab',
      'Baluchistan'],
      correctAnswer: 'Baluchistan',
    },
    {
      id: 8,
      question: 'The Greek Ambassador Deimachus of Plataea had visited the court of which of the following rulers of Magadha?',
      answers: ['Dhanananda',
      'Chandragupta Maurya',
      'Bindusara',
      'Asoka'],
      correctAnswer: 'Bindusara',
    },
    {
      id: 9,
      question: 'Which among the following ruler is known for Junagarh Rock Inscription?',
      answers: ['Rudradaman I',
      'Jivadaman',
      'Damajadasri',
      'Jayadaman'],
      correctAnswer: 'Rudradaman I',
    },
    {
      id: 10,
      question: 'Who was the creator of Ravanabadha?',
      answers: ['Kalidasa',
      'Bhatrahari',
      'Batsabhatti',
      'None of the above'],
      correctAnswer: 'Batsabhatti',
    },
  ],
};
